Guide to the New York State AFL-CIO Records WAG.031
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
New York State AFL-CIO Records
circa 1938-1997, 2007-ongoing
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
New York State AFL-CIO
WAG.031
173 Linear Feet in 173 record cartons.
4 websites in 4 archived websites.
The New York State AFL-CIO was founded in December 1958 by the merger of the separate state bodies of the American Federation of Labor and the Congress of Industrial Organizations. Materials mostly relate to the role of the New York State AFL-CIO in state politics and legislative initiatives. Among the issues well-documented in the collection are workers' compensation, unemployment insurance, minimum wage, education, and healthcare.
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist.
Scope and Content Note
The collection includes large donations of material from the files of the Federation's Legislative Department; these materials include background material, reports, correspondence and copies of proposed legislation on a wide range of topics of concern to the labor movement: housing, health care, safety issues in the workplace, immigrant rights, individual political campaigns and issues relating to collective bargaining rights. Significant portions of the collection include speeches, position papers, correspondence, clippings, publications, and reference materials used by Ludwig Jaffee during his tenure as research director (1952-1984), as well as press releases, programs, selected bills, correspondence, and other materials specifically relating to the New York State AFL-CIO's legislative program in the 1970s and 1980s. Also included are materials gathered by many officers and staff of the federation, including for the later period, files of President Edward J. Cleary and Secretary-Treasurer Paul F. Cole, both elected in 1984, as well as photographs.
Historical/Biographical Note
The New York State AFL-CIO is a statewide federation of trade unions that has its origins in the Workingmen's Assembly, founded in the mid-1860s, and the New York State Branch of the American federation of Labor, founded in 1888. The two organizations merged in 1898 to form the New York State Workingmen's Federation (whose name was changed in 1910 to the New York State Federation of Labor). Its primary aim was to lobby the state legislature in favor of legislation of concern to the labor movement. Issues of concern to the Federation included the abolition of child labor, equal pay for equal work, enactment of workmen's compensation law, shorter work hours and the protection of strikers and immigrant laborers. The federation grew steadily through the 1930s, under the leadership of its president (from 1934) George Meany, who had been a business agent for Plumbers Local 463 in New York City and brought the building trades unions into the state federation. Meany went on to become national president of the American Federation of Labor in 1940, and was later instrumental in negotiating the 1955 merger of the AFL with its rival federation the Congress of Industrial Organizations (CIO). In 1958 the New York organization followed suit and adopted the name New York State AFL-CIO. The newly merged federation quickly went on to press for and win the state's first minimum wage law, and improved insurance coverage for disabled and unemployed workers. The state federation also fought for Medicaid legislation in the 1960s and won enactment of the Taylor Law, which gave public employees in New York the right to organize and bargain collectively.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by the New York State AFL-CIO in 1984 and 1996. The accession numbers associated with this collection are 1996.011, 1996.013 and 2010.053, 2018.049, and NPA 2003.068.
http://nysaflcio.org/ was initially selected by curators and captured through the use of The California Digital Library's Web Archiving Service in 2007 as part of the Labor Unions and Organizations (U.S.) Web Archive. In 2015, these websites were migrated to Archive-It. Archive-It uses web crawling technology to capture websites at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy, from the resulting WARC file, of the website. In 2020. https://unionstrong.podbean.com/ was added. The accession number associated with this website is 2020.030. Flipbook embedded documents were added in 2022. The accession numbers associated with these websites are 2022.011, 2022.044, and 2022.063. In April 2022, https://www.youtube.com/user/nysaflcio/videos/ was added. The accession number associated with this website is 2022.057. In September 2023, https://www.youtube.com/@nysaflcio/videos/ was added. The accession number associated with this website is 2023.082.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu, (212) 998-2630 with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Take Down Policy
Archived websites are made accessible for purposes of education and research. NYU Libraries have given attribution to rights holders when possible; however, due to the nature of archival collections, we are not always able to identify this information.
If you hold the rights to materials in our archived websites that are unattributed, please let us know so that we may maintain accurate information about these materials.
If you are a rights holder and are concerned that you have found material on this website for which you have not granted permission (or is not covered by a copyright exception under US copyright laws), you may request the removal of the material from our site by submitting a notice, with the elements described below, to the special.collections@nyu.edu.
Please include the following in your notice: Identification of the material that you believe to be infringing and information sufficient to permit us to locate the material; your contact information, such as an address, telephone number, and email address; a statement that you are the owner, or authorized to act on behalf of the owner, of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed and that you have a good-faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law; a statement that the information in the notification is accurate and made under penalty of perjury; and your physical or electronic signature. Upon receiving a notice that includes the details listed above, we will remove the allegedly infringing material from public view while we assess the issues identified in your notice.
Labor laws and legislation -- United States.; Labor unions |x Political activity |x Law and legislation.; Labor movement -- New York (State); Labor laws and legislation -- New York (State); New York (State); Labor unions -- New York (State); New York State AFL-CIO; New York State Federation of Labor; Cleary, Edward J. (Edward John), 1906-; Cole, Paul F.; Jaffe, Ludwig.; New York State CIO Council; New York State AFL-CIO
- Inventory, 1
  - Aging: Clippings, 1955-1956; 1964 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Aging: General, 1956-1964 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Aging: Press Releases, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Aging: Press Releases, 1956-1962 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Aging: Programs, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Aging: Resolutions, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Aging: Statements, 1955-1966 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Aging: White House Conference, 1960-1963 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Aging: Published Materials, 1956-1963 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Anti-Semitism, 1953-1955 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Automation: Clippings and Articles, 1955-1965 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Automation: Clippings, 1953-1966 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Automation: Conferences, 1954-1963 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Automation: Publications, 1952-1969 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Automation: Publications, 1954-1965 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Automation: Statements, 1960-1965 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Automation: Statements, 1955-1965 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Automobile Insurance: Articles, Clippings, 1969-1974 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Automobile Insurance: Correspondence, 1970-1974 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Automobile Insurance: Legislation, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Automobile Insurance: Press Releases, 1970-1974 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Automobile Insurance: Reports, Bills, Official Documents, 1970-1974; 1977 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Automobile Insurance: NYS AFL-CIO Statements, 1970-1974 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Banking: General, 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Banking: General, 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Banking: General, 1969; 1974 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Banking, NYS Comm. on: Hearings, testimony, Oct 1983 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Banking, NYS Comm. on: Hearings, testimony, Oct 1983 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Banking, NYS Comm. on: Hearings, testimony, Oct 1983 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Banking, NYS Comm. on: Minutes, agendas, memos, Oct 1983 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Banking, NYS Comm. on: Hearings, testimony, Nov 21 1983 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Banking, NYS Comm. on: Hearings, testimony, Nov 22 1983 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Banking, NYS Comm. on: Hearings, testimony, Nov 22 1983 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Banking, NYS Comm. on: Hearings, testimony, Nov 23 1983 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Banking, NYS Comm. on: Minutes, agendas, memos, correspondence, Dec 1983 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Banking, NYS Comm. on: Minutes, agendas, memos, correspondence, Jan 1984 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Banking, NYS Comm. on: Hearings, testimony, Jan 10-11 1984 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Banking, NYS Comm. on: Draft Report, Jan 25 1984 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Banking, NYS Comm. on: Minutes, agendas, memos, correspondence, Feb 1984 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Banking, NYS Comm. on: Minutes, agendas, memos, correspondence, Feb 1984 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Banking, NYS Comm. on: Final Report, Feb 15, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Beverage Container Control Laws: Incl. RCC statement, 1975-1980 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Casino Gambling, 1979-1981 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Child Labor: Positions NYS AFL-CIO, 1968-1972 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Child Labor: NYS and misc. Publications, 1950-1970 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Child Labor: U.S. Dept. of Labor Publications, 1950-1969 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Civil Liberties, 1956; 1977 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Civil Rights: Clippings, articles, 1954-1963 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Civil Rights: The Nation Clippings, articles, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Civil Rights: AFL-CIO Publications, 1960-1969; 1975 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Civil Rights: NYS Publications, 1951-1971 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Civil Rights: Misc. Publications, 1950-1959 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Civil Rights: Misc. Publications, 1960-1964 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Civil Rights: AFL-CIO Statements, 1959-1977 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Civil Rights: NAACP Statements, 1958-1960 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Civil Rights: NYS AFL-CIO Statements, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Civil Rights: Misc. Statements, 1956-1960; 1970 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Collective Bargaining, 1960-1980 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Communications, Workers of America, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Communism: Statements, publications, reports, 1951-1957 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Communism: Clippings, articles, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Communism: Hearings, reports, 1951-1957 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Community Services: AFL-CIO Publications, incl. Conference proceedings, 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Community Service: CIO Publications, 1950-1958 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Community Services: NYC Central Labor Council Community Services Council Publications, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Community Services: Misc. Publications, 1950; 1961 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Community Services: AFL-CIO, CIO Statements, 1953; 1960-1961 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - CETA: Comprehensive Employment and Training Act, 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Consumers: General, 1960-1979 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Consumers: Clippings, articles, 1953-1972 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Consumers: Memoranda NYS AFL-CIO, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Consumers: Press Releases, 1956-1970 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Consumers: AFL-CIO Statements, 1966-1969 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Consumers: NYCIO Statements, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Consumers: NYS AFL-CIO, RRC Statements, 1965-1972 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Consumers: Studies, 1949-1954 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Cornell: ILR, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Cornell: Labor Advisory Committee, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Depressed Areas, 1959-1962 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Discrimination: General, 1958; 1962-1963 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Discrimination: Commission, 1948-1949 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Discrimination: Legislation, 1977-1981 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Discrimination: Publications, 1951-1963 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Discrimination: Reports, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Economy: General AFL-CIO Statements, 1964; 1974-1982 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Economy: General NYS AFL-CIO Statements, 1964-1982 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Economy: Inflation, 1964-1982 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Education: Clippings, 1949-1958 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Education: Clippings, articles, 1959-1969 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Education: NYS Comm. on Quality, CostEducation, 1969-1971 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Education: Conference, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Education: Published Material, 1950-1962 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Education: AFL-CIO Statements, 1957-1971 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Education: CIO Statements, 1952-1953 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Education: NYCIO Statements, 1953-1957 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Education: NYS AFL-CIO Statements, 1959-1971 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Education: Labor and Education, 1955-1969 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Education: Labor and Education, 1950-1969 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Elections 1956: National and NYS, incl. Union Endorsements (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Elections 1956: Statements re. Eisenhower Admin. Record 1952-1956 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Elections 1956: Voter Registration Efforts (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Elections 1957: National and NYS (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Elections 1958:National and NYS (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Elections 1960: Union Endorsements (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Elections 1960: Positions AFL-CIO (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Elections 1960: Positions Democratic Party (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Elections 1960: Positions General (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Elections 1960: Positions Republican Party (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Elections 1960: Voter Registration (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Elections 1960: Kennedy Campaign Advertising Costs (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Elections 1960: Kennedy Campaign Newspaper Advertising (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Elections 1960: Kennedy Campaign Radio and TV Advertising (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Elections 1960: Kennedy Campaign Button Distribution (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Elections 1961: NYS (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Elections 1962: NYS (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Elections 1964: National and NYS (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Elections 1965: NYS (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Elections 1966: National and NYS (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Elections 1968: National and NYS (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Elections 1969: National and NYS (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Elections 1972: NYS (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Elections 1976: National (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Employee Benefits: Omnibus Benefit Reform Law, 1982-1983 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Employee Benefits: Omnibus Benefit Reform Law, 1982-1983 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Employee Benefits: Omnibus Benefit Reform Law, 1982-1983 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Employee Benefits: Omnibus Benefit Reform Law, 1982-1983 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Employment: CETA, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Enterprise Zones, 1981-1984 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Enterprise Zones, 1981-1984 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Environment, 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Farm Labor: Correspondence, 1963-1968; 1971 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Farm Labor: Memos, 1966-1976 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Farm Labor: Minimum Wage Bill, 1981-1982 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Farm Labor: National Labor Relations Board, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Farm Labor: National Sharecroppers Fund, 1959-1967 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Farm Labor: Positions NYS AFL-CIO, 1961-1971 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Farm Labor: Printed material, 1948-1971 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Farm Labor: Reports, background, 1959-1971 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Farm Labor: Wine Industry, NYS, 1966-1967 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Firefighters, 1980-1981 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Foreign Policy: LJ Paper, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Foreign Trade: Reports, pamphlets, 1955-1967 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Health: American Medical Association, 1960-1962 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Health: Generic Drugs, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Health Insurance: AFL-CIO Statements, 1957-1983 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Health Insurance, Blue Cross: Clippings, 1957-1964 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Health Insurance, Blue Cross: Clippings, 1965-1969 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Health Insurance, Blue Cross: Clippings, 1970-1978 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Health Insurance, Blue Cross: Correspondence, memos, 1957-1976 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Health Insurance, Blue Cross: Hearings, testimony, 1957-1959 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Health Insurance, Blue Cross: Hearings, testimony, Jun 13 1960 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Health Insurance, Blue Cross: Hearings, testimony, 1964-1965 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Health Insurance, Blue Cross: Hearings, testimony, 1969-1976 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Health Insurance, Blue Cross: NYS Insurance Dept. opinions, decisions, 1957-1979 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Health Insurance, Blue Cross: NYCIO, NYS Government. press releases, 1957-1976 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Health Insurance, Blue Cross: Statistics, undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Health Insurance: Correspondence, 1963-1964 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Health Insurance: Legislation, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Health Insurance: Legislation, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Health Insurance: Legislation, 1971-1972 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Health Insurance: Reports, 1950;1965; 1969 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Health Insurance: Statements, 1963-1964 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Health Maintenance Organizations: Regulations, legislation, 1971-1975 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Health Maintenance Organizations: Research, pamphlets, 1979-1977 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Health: Medical Malpractice clippings, 1975-1976 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Health: Medical Malpractice legislation, 1972-1975 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Health: Medical Services, 1959-1962 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Health, Medicare & Medicaid: Articles, 1967-1976 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Health, Medicare & Medicaid: Medical Advisory Comm., 1972-1973 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Health, Medicare & Medicaid: Medical Advisory Comm., 1974 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Health, Medicare & Medicaid: Medical Advisory Comm., 1975 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Health, Medicare & Medicaid: Medical Advisory Comm., 1977-1980 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Health, Medicare & Medicaid: Positions, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Health, Medicare & Medicaid: Reports, 1966-1976 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Health, Medicare & Medicaid: Statements, 1966-1975 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Health, Medicare & Medicaid: Statements, 1968; 1976-1977 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Health, Medicare & Medicaid: Title XIX of Social Security Act of 1966 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Housing: CIO Housing Committee, 1952-1955 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Housing: AFL-CIO Activities, 1959-1961 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Housing: NYS and NYC, 1951-1955; 1965 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Housing: Rent Control, 1951-1960 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Immigration, 1952-1975 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Income Maintenance: War on Poverty, Welfare, 1949-1969 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Industrial Commissioner NYS, 1981-1983 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Industrial Dislocation, 1955-1965 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Insurance: Articles, clippings, 1971-1982 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Insurance: Conflict of Interest, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Insurance: Committee, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Insurance: Legislation, 1980-1981 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Insurance: Regulatory Reform, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Insurance: Reports, 1971-1972 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Insurance: Statements, positions, 1969-1982 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Insurance: Statements, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Insurance: Statistics, 1970s (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Interest Rates: NYS AFL-CIO positions, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - International Trade: Statements, articles, reports, 1974-1983 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Job Training: General, 1982-1983 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Job Training: NYS Coordinating Council, 1982-1983 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Job Training: Workshop, Jan 1983 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Job Training: Handbook, Nov 1983 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Juvenile Delinquency: NYSFL, NYCIO, NYS AFL-CIO statements, 1955-1962 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Labor: Committee, 1977-1980 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Labor: Committee, 1977-1980 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Labor: Committee, 1977-1980 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Labor: Committee, 1976-1979 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Labor: Statements, 1963-1968 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Labor: Statements, 1949-1963 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Labor: Statements, 1949-1963 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Labor: Statements, undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Labor: Statements, 1954-1964 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Labor: Crime, Corruption, 1950-1959 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Labor: Crime, Corruption, 1960-1962 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Labor: Crime, Corruption, 1957-1959 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Labor: Crime, Corruption, 1957-1958 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Labor: History, 1938-1955 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Labor: Labor Law, 1966; 1975-1978 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Labor: Labor-Management Relations, 1955-1966 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Labor: Labor-Management Relations, 1954-1977 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Labor: Labor-Management Relations, 1955-1977 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Labor: Labor-Management Relations, Collective Bargaining, 1954-1979 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Labor: Labor-Management Relations, Collective Bargaining, 1950-1965 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Labor: Landrum-Griffin Act, 1959-1960 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Labor, NYS Dept. of, 1981-1983 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Labor: Organizational Picketing, 1957-1959 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Legal Services: Group/Pre-Paid Legal Services, 1972-1974 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Legal Services: Group/Pre-Paid Legal Services, 1975-1976 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Legal Services: Municipal Emp. Legal Services Fund Inc., 1975-1977 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Legal Services: Municipal Emp. Legal Services Fund Inc., 1975-1977 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Lie Detectors, 1964-1976 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Lobbies: General, 1975-1978 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Lobbies: Lobbying Registration NYS AFL-CIO, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Loyalty Oaths, 1950-1969 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Manpower and Retraining, 1958-1968 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Minimum Wage, 1957-1975 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Monopolies, 1947-1976 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Mortgage Rates: Redlining, 1977-1982 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - New York City: Battery Park City, 1976-1980 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - New York City: General, 1961-1963 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - New York City: General, 1978-1980 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - New York City: Westchester Referendum, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - New York City: Westway, 1977-1983 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - New York State: Constitutional Convention 1967, 1978-1979 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - New York State: Constitutional Convention 1967 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - New York State: Constitutional Convention 1967 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - New York State: Constitutional Convention 1967 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - New York State: Constitutional Convention 1967 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - New York State: Constitutional Convention 1967 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - New York State: Constitutional Convention 1967 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - New York State: Governor, 1976-1980 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - New York State: Governor, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 9)